<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pablo Overton</title>
    <link>https://www.pablooverton.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pablo Overton</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 15:59:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.pablooverton.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anathem Syntactic</title>
      <link>https://www.pablooverton.com/posts/anathem-syntactic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 15:59:28 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.pablooverton.com/posts/anathem-syntactic/</guid>
      <description>Exploring Syntactic Faculties and Philosophical Depth in Neal Stephenson&amp;rsquo;s Anathem 🔗As a software professional with an interest in both technology and literature, I recently found myself rereading the speculative fiction novel Anathem by Neal Stephenson. This book, with its richly detailed world-building and thought-provoking themes, offers a unique blend of speculative fiction and philosophical inquiry that resonates deeply with anyone interested in the intersection of technology, language, and human cognition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.pablooverton.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 11:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.pablooverton.com/about/</guid>
      <description>As a Lead Data Engineer, I&amp;rsquo;ve spearheaded large-scale projects, efficiently transforming complex business requirements into resilient data architectures and pipelines. My role extends beyond technical expertise; I&amp;rsquo;m a mentor, coach, and a staunch advocate for software engineering best practices within my team.&#xA;Outside the office, I&amp;rsquo;m deeply engaged with open-source software and constantly exploring the forefront of machine learning and AI technologies. I actively participate in hackathons and enjoy working on IoT projects, blending my passion for both hardware and software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data as a Product: Transforming Teams and Avoiding Common Pitfalls</title>
      <link>https://www.pablooverton.com/posts/data-as-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 11:48:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.pablooverton.com/posts/data-as-product/</guid>
      <description>Introduction 🔗In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced world of data engineering, one paradigm shift can revolutionize how teams function and deliver value: treating data as a product. This mindset not only enhances team operations but also ensures the data produced is reliable, usable, and valuable across the organization.&#xA;The Data as a Product Mindset 🔗Picture yourself as a baker in a bustling bakery. Each loaf of bread you create isn&amp;rsquo;t just a one-off experiment; it&amp;rsquo;s a product designed to meet customer needs, ensure satisfaction, and drive sales.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
